我叫巴里 艾伦
My name is Barry Allen.
我是世上速度最快的人
I am the fastest man alive.
在我11岁的时候 我的妈妈被谋杀了
When I was 11, my mother was murdered.
我看到了一团闪电一样的东西
I saw a ball of lightning.
闪电里面有一个人
Inside the lightning there was a man.
他杀了我妈
He killed my mom.
我对天发誓 不是我干的
I swear to god I didn't do this.
妈妈在哪里 那天晚上发生的事情
- Where's mom? - What happened that night
匪夷所思
was impossible.
然后一个意外事故让我更加匪夷所思
Then an accident made me the impossible.
你一直昏迷着
- - You were in a coma.
多久 9个月
- For how long? - Nine months.
你的肌肉本该萎缩的
Your muscles should be atrophied,
但反而是出现细胞再生状态
but instead they're in a state of cellular regeneration.
我不是唯一一个受影响的 是吗
I wasn't the only one affected, was I?
我们也在寻找其他像你一样的变异人
We've been searching for other meta humans like yourself.
我的一生 都想做更多的好事
All my life I've wanted to do more.
我第一次有机会帮助别人 我却把它弄砸了
And the first chance I get to help someone, I screw up.
你的功绩远远大于错误
The good you do must far outweigh the bad.
你很快就能出狱了
You're not gonna be in here much longer.
无论谁杀了妈妈  我想我终于有办法
Whoever killed mom, I think I finally have a way
可以找到他们
to find them.
在这个部分我好像应该
This is the part where I'm supposed to do the whole
自我介绍了
intro thingy.
巴里·艾伦 速度最快的人
Barry Allen, fastest man alive...
但你们都已经知道了
But you know all that already.
好吧 一起去做点好事吧
All right, let's get to the good stuff.
看见那片烟雾了吗 那是市中心
You see that smoke? That's a fire
西街和第三大街处发生火灾了
on Western and 3rd in downtown Central City.
而那团模糊的影子 那是正在去现场路上的我
And that blur? That's me on my way to it.
以每小时352英里的速度飞驰着
I'm going 352 miles an hour.
这已经是慢速了
And it's a slow day.
这里是云梯队52号
This is Ladder 52.
我们还要至少2分钟后才能到达
We're still at least two minutes out.
那是现场的人会死的
People are gonna die in there.
我知道
I know.
巴里
Barry?
Barry!
什么 我错过了吗
What? Did I miss it?
你冲过头了 差不多过了6个街区
You overshot by about six blocks.
我的错
My bad.
佩琪
Paige!
我的女儿 有没有人看到我的女儿
My daughter! Has anyone seen my daughter?
佩琪 哇哦
Paige! Whoa!
到了吗
You there yet?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
没干什么
Nothing.
你在跟谁说话
Who were you talking to?
-没有啊 -你是不是在跟巴里说话
- No one. - Are you talking to Barry?
-谁 是巴里·艾伦吗
- Who? - Barry Allen?
被闪电击中的那个人 昏迷了9个月的那个人
Struck by lighting? Was in a coma for nine months?
醒了之后能够跑得比声速还快的那个人
Woke up being able to run faster than the speed of sound?
记起来了没  没有
Ring a bell? No.
没有跟他讲话
Haven't talked to him.
思科 这里到处都是火
Cisco, there's fire everywhere!
思科 你还在吗
Cisco, are you still there?
妈
Mom?
妈妈
Mommy!
-哇哦 -妈咪
- Whoa! - Mommy!
所有人都救出来了
Everybody's out.
还有其他任务吗 思科
What else you got for me, Cisco?
巴里 我是凯特琳
Barry, it's Caitlin.
嘿 凯特琳
Hey, Caitlin.
你好吗
How's your day?
马上科技之星实验室
Get back to S.T.A.R. Labs. Now.
马上回去
On my way.
噢
Oh.
你们两个脑子都进水了吗
Have you both lost your minds?
你们以为自己是谁啊
Who do you think you are?
我是千里眼和顺风耳 他是快足啊
Well, I'm the eyes and ears, and he's the feet.
这一点都不好笑
This isn't funny.
你这是在自杀
You could have gotten yourself killed.
你不能像个超速救火队似的
You can't be running around the city
在城市里乱跑
like some supersonic fireman.
为什么不能
Why not?
这是我们说好的啊 我用我的速度做好事
This is what we talked about: Me using my speed to do good.
我们说的是你帮我们控制
We talked about you helping us contain
其他可能被粒子加速器爆炸
other people who might have been affected
影响到的人
by the particle accelerator explosion.
控制变异人
Meta-humans.
而除了克莱德 马顿 我们还没有找到其他人
And aside from Clyde Mardon, we haven't found any.
这座城市的人们仍然需要帮助
People in this city still need help.
而我可以帮他们
- - And I can help them.
我们可以帮他们
We can help them.
你能说点什么吗
Will you please say something?
我认为凯特琳是说
I think what Caitlin is saying,
用这么独特的生气态度是想说
in her own spectacularly angry way,
是我们才刚开始了解
is that we are just beginning to understand
你的身体能够做什么
what your body is capable of.
不是我想啰嗦什么  但艾伦先生
Not to sound like a broken record, Mr. Allen...
我认为还是谨慎克制比较好
I do caution restraint.
韦尔斯博士
Dr. Wells...
我怀疑谨慎克制就是你会变成今天的这个样子的原因
I doubt restraint is how you got to be the man you are today.
在轮椅上维持生命
In a wheelchair and a pariah.
缺少克制才是造成今天种种事情的原因
Lack of restraint is what made me these things.
量力而为吧
Know your limits.
别期望每次你闯祸
don't expect me to patch you up
我都会帮你补救
every time you break something.
嘿 今天有发生什么事情吗
Hey, uh... Anything happen out there today?
这件衣服的传感器回传了
The sensors in the suit were kicking back
一些奇怪的遥测数据 看起来像是你的脉搏持续飙升几秒
some weird telemetry, like your vitals spiked for a few seconds.
我感觉再好不过了
Never felt better.
嘿 乔 一切都还好吗
Hey, Joe, everything all right?
好极了 我在案发现场
Great. I got a fresh crime scene...
有一具尸体
A dead body...
刑警正在询问目击者
Detectives interviewing witnesses...
已经拉好了黄色警戒线
miles of that yellow tape stretched over everything.
万事俱备只欠东风了 你能猜到是什么吗
I'm only missing one thing. Can you guess what that is?
我马上过去
I'll be right there.
工作召唤我了
My day job beckons.
你觉得他什么时候才会发现
When do you think he'll realize
他没换衣服
he didn't take his clothes?
嗯
Hmm.
罪犯带走了几把手枪
Perp made off with a bunch of handguns,
其中至少有六支格洛克19型手枪
at least six Glock 19s
还有额外加倍的弹药
fitted with extra ammunition magazines.
有人正准备大干一场啊
Somebody's looking to do a whole lot of bad.
嘿 不要意思 我来迟了
Hey, sorry I'm late.
艾伦 是去买秋装了吗 艾伦先生
Doing a little fall shopping, Mr. Allen?
噢
Oh.
早上出来太匆忙了 都没注意到
I was going so fast this morning, I didn't even notice.
噢
Oh.
嗯
Yeah.
我下载了这里的监控录像
I downloaded the surveillance footage off the video camera.
看起来只有一个罪犯
Looks like only one perp.
录像上可能只有一个人 但实际上有六个人
Footage may only show one, but it was six guys.
看这些脚印 它们都交错在一起
Look, the tracks. They're all crossing each other.
六双脚印 六把枪被盗
Six sets of footprints. Six guns stolen.
我们追捕的应该是个犯罪团伙
We should be looking for a crew.
呃……怪了
Huh... Weird.
这鞋印 看着似乎都是一个码
The shoes, it looks like they're all the same size.
我猜是男性十码
Men's tens, I'd guess.
和你一样的鞋码 队长
Just like you, Captain.
不是说你是嫌疑犯 长官 我
Not that you're a suspect, sir. I--
你一心多用的能力真是出人意表啊
Your ability to multi-task is truly remarkable.
中城警局
你总是能在同一时间让我 队长和你自己都
The way you can embarrass me, the captain, and yourself
很尴尬 乔 抱歉
all at the same time. Joe, I'm sorry.
你老是跟我说这句话 乔 抱歉
I'm starting to think "Joe, I'm sorry" Is
我都开始怀疑 乔 抱歉 是不是我的真名了
my actual name considering how often you say it to me.
我现在要处理的事很多
I'm dealing with a lot right now.
好吧 我知道
Look, I know you are.
相信我 我要处理的事情也很多
Believe me, I'm dealing with it, too.
以前我的想法一直都很简单
I've always had a very simple set of beliefs.
重力使物体下落 水让事物潮湿
Gravity makes things fall. Water makes things wet.
几个礼拜前 我还相信
And up until a few weeks ago, I believed
世界上跑得最快的人跑完一英里需要4分钟
the fastest man could run a mile in four minutes.
而不是4秒钟
Not four seconds.
我3秒钟就能跑完
I could do it in three.
好吧 这不相干
Not relevant.
你没有跟艾瑞斯说这一切吧
You haven't said anything to Iris about all this, have you?
没有 我答应你了 我会遵守承诺的
No, I made you a promise. I keep my promises.
你继续撒谎吧
Keep on lying like that.
你还会遭雷劈的
You're liable to get struck by lightning again.
回你实验室去 开始着手分析
Get up to the lab. Start processing the evidence
那枪械店拿回来的证据
from the gun store.
嘿 艾瑞斯
Hey,Iris.
巴里又逃学了吗
Did Barry run away again?
除非那是你作业本上的问题之一 小美女
Unless that's one of your homework questions, little lady,
不然就不关你的事
it's none of your business.
回你的房间去
Go on back to your room.
我要见我爸爸
I want to see my dad.
我说过不可以 巴里
I already said no, Barry.
那些事不是他干的 他没有伤害我的妈妈
He didn't do those things. He didn't hurt my mom.
那天晚上我就在现场 我看见了
I was there that night. I saw.
当时有个男人 好 我知道
There was a man. Yeah, I know.
我们已经谈过这些了
We've gone through this already.
那为什么我不可以去见他
Then why can't I go see him?
因为我说不可以
Because I said so.
你又不是我爸 你无权告诉我该做什么
You're not my father! You can't tell me what to do!
现在 我是那个唯一一个关心你
Right now, I am the only adult that gives a damn
遭遇到了什么事情的大人 所以 我有权告诉你该做什么
what happens to you, so yes, I can tell you what to do.
现在回你的房间去
Now go to your room.
我讨厌你
I hate you!
都是你的错
This is all of your fault.
我本来可以选修欧洲民俗学
I could have taken European folklore
来达到社会学学分要求的 但是我没有
to cover my sociology requirement, but no.
因为你说 学新闻学吧 艾瑞斯
You said, "Take journalism, Iris.
当记者最好玩了
Reporters have all of the fun."
你猜怎么了 巴里 当记者一点都不好玩
Guess what, Barry? Reporters have none of the fun.
新闻学很枯燥 我很无聊
Journalism is boring. I'm bored.
都怪你 干嘛
I blame you. What?
你干嘛那样看我
Why are you staring at me like that?
你看起来很赞
You look really nice.
谢谢
Thanks.
你干嘛不好好打扮下
Why don't you look nice?
今天下午 穿正装戴领带
This afternoon? Suit and tie?
学校要颁予西蒙·斯塔格
The university is giving Simon Stagg...
-西蒙·斯塔格 -一个大奖
- Simon Stagg. - Some big award.
还有你答应 帮你解释你报道中
And you agreed-- to explain the science stuff
那些科学知识 我现在都想起来了
for your article. It's all coming back to me now.
你回家换衣服要多久
How fast can you get home and change?
呃 很快
Uh, pretty fast.
嘿 艾伦
Hey, Allen.
乔让我来看看你对枪械店拿回来的证据
Joe asked me to see where you're at
分析到哪里了
on the evidence from the gun store shooting.
嘿 艾瑞斯
Oh, hey, Iris.
警官
Detective.
拜托 你们想亲就亲吧
Please, guys, uh, just kiss already.
我已经知道了 记得吧
I already know, remember?
额 谢谢你这么爽快 巴里
Ah. Thanks for being so cool about this, Barry.
我知道要守着一个大秘密不容易
I know it's not easy keeping a big secret.
我正在习惯
I'm getting used to it.
我觉得这是十分卓越非凡的
I find it quite remarkable,
从一个中城大学的
having once been a timid freshman
感谢他在器官移植领域上的贡献
年度风云人物
青涩胆怯的大一新生
at Central City University,
成长为诸位眼前的我
to be standing before you now,
由董事会评选出的年度风云人物
the regents choice for man of the year.
我很感激颁发这个奖项给我
While I very much appreciate the award,
对我来说 真正的荣耀是知道
the real honor for me is knowing that
我在器官移植方面的努力能够
my work in organ transference
帮助人们获得人生第二次生命
helps give people a second chance at life.
感谢各位今天的到来
Thank you all very much for coming.
好了 首先
Okay. All right, first things first...
西蒙舞台主要的研究领域是细胞克隆
Simon Stagg's work in cellular cloning
现在已经取得巨大的成就
has led to huge advancements
器官移植的前景
in the future of organ replacement...
记者在工作的时候可以喝酒吗
Are journalists allowed to drink on the job?
好吧 如果你已经开始觉得无聊了
Okay. If you are bored already,
那还是得等我们讲到细胞再生
just wait till we get to the science behind
背后的科学才行
cellular regeneration.
好怀念这种感觉啊 巴里
I have missed this, Barry.
我觉得在你从昏迷中醒来之后
I feel like we haven't spent any quality time together
我们貌似都没有好好待在一起了
since you woke up from the coma.
是呀 我知道我这几周过得很疯狂
Yeah, I've had a crazy few weeks, I know.
我还以为你因为埃迪一直在避开我
I thought maybe you'd been avoiding me because of Eddie.
我知道你觉得我和我爸爸的搭档在一起不好
I know you think it's wrong, me dating my dad's partner,
但我就是 -不
and I just-- No.
不是这样的 完全不是
That is not it. At all.
噢噢
Oh! Oh!
斯塔格先生 我能否在我的文章中引用
Mr. Stagg, I was wondering if I could get a quote from you
您的话 现在不行 女士
for my article. Not now, miss.
-我还是自己编点什么吧
- I'll just make something up. -
你要和我说什么
So... What were you gonna tell me?
你看起来似乎有话要说
You looked like you were about to say something.
是
Yeah--
啊
- - Ah!
安静 所有的人
Quiet down! All of you!
噢 天哪
Oh, my God.
安静
Quiet!
考虑多么周到啊
How considerate!
你们都戴着你们最好的珠宝
You're all wearing your finest jewelry!
简直就像你们知道我们回来抢劫一样
Almost like you knew we were coming to rob you!
现在所有人排好队
Now everybody line up!
不要 不要
Don't. Don't.
不许动
Freeze!
放 放 下你的武器
D-d-drop your weapons!
闪电侠
第一季 第二集
巴里
Barry.
Barry!
我转身就不见你了
I turned around and you were gone.
发生什么事了 你没事吧
What happened? Are you okay?
嗯 我没事
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine. I...
我追着他们 想要看清车牌号码
I went after them to try and get the plates.
-什么 -然后我
- Wha--? - And I...
我晕倒了
I fainted.
-嗨  - 艾瑞斯
- Hi. - Iris.
你在哪
Where were you?
爸 别紧张
Dad, go easy.
我在外面找到他的 他晕倒了
I found him outside. He fainted.
需要我帮你找个医护人员吗 艾伦
You want me to get you a paramedic, Allen?
不用 我没事 谢谢 埃迪
No, I'm fine. Thanks, Eddie.
我以为我死定了
I thought I was dead.
我看见他开枪了 然后--轰的一声
I saw the gun go off, and then-- boom.
突然我就在外面了
Suddenly I'm outside.
我不知道我怎么到那里的
I have no idea how I got there.
可以和你说两句话吗
Let me talk to you for a second.
当然
Yeah.
你去追那些持枪者了 是吧
You chased those gunmen, didn't you?
是的 他们应该就是上次的犯人
Yeah, they must be the same guys
早上抢劫枪械店的那群人
that knocked over the gun shop earlier today.
逮到他们的话 你打算怎么办
And what were you going to do when you caught them?
哈？
Huh?
好声好气的请他们把车停在路边吗
Ask them nicely to pull over?
你又不是枪弹不入的
You're not bulletproof.
等等 你是吗
Wait. Are you?
-不是 但是 -行了
- No, but-- - Okay.
不要再逞英雄了
No more heroics.
追捕坏人不是你的工作
Chasing bad guys is not your job.
那是我的工作 你又不是警察
It's mine. You're not a cop.
答应我
Promise me.
答应你
Promise.
还有你也知道艾瑞斯又不傻
And you know Iris is not stupid.
找个比晕倒更好的借口吧
Start making better excuses than "I fainted."
我……
I...
你骗了我们
You lied to us.
你怎么可以不告诉我们你有阵发性眩晕的症状
How could you not tell us you're experiencing dizzy spells?
我们是你的医生
We're your doctors.
神才知道你体内发生了什么
God knows what's going on inside your body.
你的细胞现在正处于不断的变化中
Your cells are in a constant state of flux.
你可能会出现心肺衰竭
You could be experiencing cardiopulmonary failure
或是短暂性脑缺血
or a transient ischemic attack.
还有轻度中风 也可能不会
Mini stroke. Probably not.
在所有人之中 你应该知道 科学界的研究是要共享
You of all people should know that in science, we share.
我们从不遮遮掩掩
We do not keep secrets.
哇 在罗尼之后我就没见过
Wow... I haven't seen anyone
有谁能让她那么生气了
make her that angry since Ronnie.
罗尼是凯特琳的未婚夫
Ronnie was Caitlin's fiance?
那晚因为加速器爆炸而死去的人
The one that died the night of the accelerator explosion?
是的 他
Yeah. He is...
失踪了
missed.
现在
Now...
我们来弄清楚为什么这个会发生在你身上
Let's figure out why this is happening to you.
我们准备好了
We're all set.
一点缓冲物 以防万一
A little padding. Just in case.
好的
Yeah.
你确定吗 思科
You're sure about this, Cisco?
大多数家用跑步机都有最大限速
Most home treadmills have a maximum speed of about
大概是12英里每小时
12 miles per hour.
这个被我改造了
This one has been Cisco'ed.
相信我 这个能承受你的速度
Trust me. It can handle your speed.
好的
Okay.
心率 血压 神经传导都正常
Heart rate, blood pressure, nerve conduction all normal.
保佑巴里
For Barry.
脑电波也一切正常
Brainwave function within standard limits.
我说过
I told you
那个跑步机能承受的
the treadmill could take it.
凯瑟琳
Caitlin.
注意看血糖指数
Look at the glucose levels.
哦天哪 当然了
Oh, my God. Of course.
-是吗 -太明显了
- Right? - It was so obvious.
血糖指数 巴里
Glucose levels. Barry!
我们应该已经知道你为什么
We think we know why you keep--
老是昏迷了
passing out.
巴里
Barry!
巴里去哪儿了
Where's Barry?
在洗澡
Taking a shower.
下午三点去洗澡
At three o'clock in the afternoon?
楼上能找到巴里吗
If I go up those stairs, am I gonna see Barry Allen?
或者还是你愿意被禁足一个星期 因为你撒了谎
Or are you gonna be grounded for a week for lying to me?
对不起 爸爸
I'm sorry, Daddy.
不用担心 我知道他去哪里了
But don't worry. I know where he went.
我也是
Me too.
我又昏迷了吗
I passed out again?
是一种代谢性的紊乱
Total metabolic failure
由急剧发生的低血糖引起
brought on by acute hypoglycemia.
是我没有吃够么
I'm not eating enough.
所以我挂一袋葡萄糖就可以走人了
So an I.V. Bag and I'm good to go?
也许得40袋
Try 40.
我想你一定渴了
Guess you were thirsty.
我们得根据你的新的代谢性情况来指定
We're gonna need to fashion you a new diet
一个适合你的饮食计划
based on your metabolic changes.
我做了些计算 你需要吃大概
I've done a few calculations. You need to consume
和850份玉米饼一样多的食物
an amount equal to roughly 850 tacos.
但是如果换成起司汉堡的话
Unless we're talking cheese and guac,
那就得是另一种算法了
which is like a whole other set of equations.
要吃墨西哥菜的话 我向你推荐布鲁克纳大街
For Mexican, I recommend Tito's.
的迪多斯餐馆
On Bruckner Avenue?
他们有全城最好吃的墨西哥卷饼
Best burrito in the city.
韦斯特警长
Detective West.
什么风把你吹到科技之星实验室了
What brings you to S.T.A.R. Labs?
我在你的实验室没找到你
When I couldn't find you at your lab,
我就做了些调查
I started doing a little research.
结果我发现一个地图 红色的线条画满了这个城市
Turns out there's been reports of a red streak around the city,
惩治抢劫犯 把人们从着火的楼房救出来
stopping muggers, rescuing people from burning buildings.
你没跟他说我们是一起的
You didn't tell him we were working together?
乔 听我解释
Joe, I can explain.
你在法院已经有一份正当工作了 巴里
You already have a job in law enforcement, Barry.
我建议你还是回去做你的本职工作
I suggest you get back to it.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
别看我 我是支持你的
Don't look at me. I'm on your side.
警长
Detective.
我们都是为了巴里好
We all want what's best for Barry.
如果你真是为了巴里好的话
If you wanted what was best for Barry,
你应该让他摆脱现在的困境
you'd try to talk him out of this lunacy
而不是鼓励他去拿生命冒险
instead of encouraging him going out there risking his life.
你看到了一个能控制天气的人
You saw a man control the weather.
你觉得警察会怎么对付这样的人
What are the police gonna do against someone like that?
自从加速器爆炸以后
Since the accelerator explosion
我们认为可能还有更多这样的人存在
we suspect there may be more like him.
你准备怎么做
And you're gonna do what?
把他们捉起来么
Catch them?
你疯了吗
Are you insane?
你觉得就是跑的快点儿
You think because you can run real fast
你就无敌了吗 你不是
that you're invincible? You're not!
你只是个孩子
You're just a kid.
我的孩子
My kid.
我不是你的孩子 乔
I'm not your kid, Joe.
你也不是我的父亲
And you're not my father.
我的父亲正在监狱里蹲着
My father's sitting in Iron Heights.
被污蔑有罪
Wrongfully convicted.
你根本错怪了他
You were wrong about him.
你也不了解这一切
And you're wrong about this.
现在也许我帮不了他什么
Now I may not be able to help him,
但是如果我有能力把人们从着火的楼房里救出来
but if I can save someone from a burning building
或者阻止武装的歹人 那我一定会去做
or stop some armed thieves, I'm gonna do it.
你阻止不了我
And you can't stop me.
别劝我了
So don't try.
你自以为聪明
You think you're so smart.
你们都是
All of you.
但是还有些事你们不知道
But you don't know what you don't know.
我希望你们能聪明到在出人命之前
And I hope that you're clever enough to figure it out
把这一切都想通
before somebody gets killed.
你们剩下的人呢
Where's the rest of your crew?
只有我
Just me.
你想要什么 布莱克
What do you want, black?
我活着的最大愿望就是
The only thing I still want in life...
你头儿的死
Your boss dead.
这不是我的错 是你们行动太迟缓
It's not my fault you and your team moved too slow.
我告诉你斯塔格会在哪儿 而不是他会在那儿呆多久
I told you where Stagg would be, not how long he'd be there.
我想要他的行程表
I need his full itinerary.
和他的办公室以及家里的安全密码
And security access to his office and home.
去你的
Screw you.
在安保行业我是有头有脸的
I've got a reputation in the security business.
我孤立我的老板是一回事
It's one thing if my employer gets iced.
让他在自己的房间里受到伤害又是另一回事
It's another if it happens in his bedroom.
你会按我说的去做的 加瓦先生
You'll do what I ask, Mr. Java.
没有你的队伍 你能拿我何
What the hell are you gonna do to me without your army?
我就是一个队伍
I am an army.
再来吼我试试啊
Come to yell at me again?
西蒙斯塔格的安保队长昨晚被杀害了
Simon Stagg's head of security was murdered last night.
验尸官弄到了一点皮肤样本
The coroner took some skin samples.
希望是凶手的
Hopefully they belong to the killer.
看看你能不能找到匹配的
See if you can find a match.
昨晚斯塔格的财产也受到了损失
Can't be a coincidence that Stagg's benefit
这绝不是巧合
was attacked last night.
我现在要去拜访斯塔格
I'm going to interview Stagg now.
-我和你一起去 - 你留下来工作
- I'll come with you. - Your job is in here.
呆在这儿
Stay in here and do it.
-嗨 老爸 -嗨 亲爱的
- Hey, Dad. - Hey, baby.
得闪了
Gotta go.
我爸怎么又对你生气了
Why is my dad mad at you?
工作上的事
Work stuff.
你干嘛对我生气
Why are you mad at me?
你应该在基特斯和我碰面
You were supposed to meet me at jitters
给我的文章提供一下科学背景资料
to give me some scientific background for my article.
我爽约了
And I didn't show up.
现在我不得不在24小时内再想一个新的文章题目
And now I have to come up with a new article topic in 24 hours
要不然我就完成不了作业
or I fail the assignment.
-艾瑞斯 -别跟我道歉
- Iris-- - Don't say that you're sorry.
好 我知道你很抱歉
Okay, I know that you are.
但是我不知道的是你到底怎么了
What I don't know is what is going on with you.
我们在同一间屋檐下长大
- - We grew up one bedroom down
你真以为我不知道
from each other. Do you honestly think that
你什么时候高兴
I don't know when you're happy?
伤心 沮丧还是失落吗
Or sad or depressed or lost?
我最后再问你一次 巴里 艾伦
I'm gonna ask you one last time, Barry Allen,
你最好诚实点回答我
and you better be honest with me.
你到底
What the--
你想知道发生了什么
You want to know what's happening.
我变快了
I'm fast now.
上帝 我只是想告诉你
God, I just want to tell you.
我的感受
How I feel.
你给我的感受
How you make me feel.
但是我不能
But I can't.
你到底怎么了
Hell is going on with you?
我们还没谈完呢
We are not done talking about this.
不可能
That's impossible.
这也是昨晚的凶手
There was a murder last night.
这些皮肤细胞是属于凶手的
These skin cells belong to the murderer,
但这些细胞是原初细胞
but these cells are naive.
干细胞可以自我复制
Stem cells that they can replicate
分析完成
变成身体需要的任何细胞
and become any cell the body needs.
它们只能来自于婴儿
They only come from babies.
这意味着你的杀手是什么 一个新生儿吗
This means your killer is what, a newborn?
你真的认为有人想杀我吗
You honestly think that someone wants to kill me?
嗯 我们不确定 斯塔格先生 但
Well, we're not sure, Mr. Stagg, but...
你的荣誉事件在枪口下被抢劫
An event you were being honored at was robbed at gunpoint.
而且今天早晨发现你的安保主管被杀害了
And your head of security was found murdered this morning.
我是一个科学家和慈善家
I am a scientist and a philanthropist.
通常我们不会是刺客的靶子
We're not often the targets of assassins.
嗯 那那些诉讼呢
Well...What about lawsuits?
其中有20个是针对你的
You got about 20 of those pending against you.
这就是可悲的现实 警长
It is a sad fact of life, Detective, that
当你挣了一大笔财富
when you earn a lot of money,
那些没钱的人就认为他们能拿走你的
people who haven't think they can take yours.
举个例子 人们喜欢这个家伙吗
People like this guy, for example?
丹东·布莱克
Danton Black?
Danton Black.
你解雇了他 现在他在控诉你
You fired him. Now he's suing you.
很不幸 我们的工作关系不顺利
Unfortunately, our working relationship wasn't successful,
但我能向你们俩担保一件事
but I can assure you both of one thing.
丹东·布莱克
Danton Black...
不是一个杀手
Is not a killer.
他是个临床研究员 而不是一个犯罪策划者
He's a clinical researcher, not a criminal mastermind.
现在 只要我能帮得上忙的地方 尽管告诉我
Now, if I can help you in any way, please let me know.
我和你一样希望那些人尽快被抓住
I want these people caught as much as you.
我们就在这
Then here we are!
趴下
Down!
队长 发生了什么
Captain, what's going on?
现在不是时候 巴里 一个武装持枪歹徒
Not now, Barry. An armed gunman
正在斯塔格公司射杀
is shooting up Stagg industries.
乔在那
Joe's there.
带他离开 我来掩护你
Get him out of here. I'll cover you.
好了吗 走
Ready? Go.
快走
Go!
不
No.
不管你是谁 投降吧
Whoever you are, give yourself up.
对不起
Sorry.
我们哪也不去
We are not going anywhere.
除非西蒙·斯塔格死了
Until Simon Stagg is dead.
对不起
Sorry.
擦伤已经在急速地愈合
The abrasions are already rapidly healing.
是啊 我被打趴了
Yeah, I got my ass handed to me.
你把血弄到我的套装上了
You got blood on my suit.
我认为有一部分是他的血
I think some of it belongs to him.
另一个不太友好的变种人
Another not-so-friendly meta-human.
丹东·布莱克
Danton Black.
他是个生物遗传学者
He's a bio-geneticist
专门研究治疗性克隆
specialized in therapeutic cloning.
培植新的器官去代替老化的
Growing new organs to replace failing ones.
显然斯塔格偷了他的研究 然后把他解雇了
Apparently Stagg stole his research and then fired him.
我看到布莱克从他自己的身体创造出复制体
I saw Black create duplicates from his own body.
那可相当讽刺
That's pretty ironic.
这个家伙专门研究克隆
The guy specialized in cloning
而现在他能复印他自己
and now he can make xeroxes of himself.
如果他正在用自己做实验时
If he was experimenting on himself
刚好暴露在粒子加速器爆炸
when he was exposed to the dark matter wave
所释放出的暗物质波中的话
released by the particle accelerator explosion--
遇到克隆队长了耶
Meet Captain clone.
不用担心
Don't worry.
我会想到更炫酷的名字的
I'll come up with something cooler.
你去哪
Where are you going?
乔说的对
Joe was right.
我完全没有弄清楚状况
I'm in way over my head.
是的 我很快 但我不是战士
Yeah, I'm fast, but I am no warrior.
伙计 我几乎连一个变种人都打败不了 更不用说六个了
Man, I could barely fight one meta-human, let alone six.
巴里
Barry.
我明白
I understand.
今天是个挫折
Today was a setback.
但任何伟大的事业都会有
But any grand enterprise has them.
不失败几次我们是学不会飞翔的
And we can never learn to fly without crashing a few times.
这不是什么伟大事业 韦尔斯博士
This wasn't a grand enterprise, Dr. Wells.
这就是个错误
This was a mistake.
爸爸
Dad!
对不起 禁止身体接触
Sorry. No physical contact.
五分钟 艾伦
Five minutes, Allen.
坐下来 儿子
Sit down, son.
巴里 你怎么到这来的
Barry, how did you get here?
我自己跑来的 乔不肯带我来
I ran here. Joe wouldn't bring me.
他不让我见你
He wouldn't let me see you.
我恨他 不 不
I hate him. No, no.
别 别这么说
Don't--don't say that.
不是乔不想你来这
It isn't Joe that doesn't want you to come here.
是我不想你来这
I don't want you to come here.
我不想让你看到我现在这个样子
I don't want you to see me like this.
你必须放他走
You have to let him go.
我爸爸没有做过那些事
My dad didn't do these things.
他没有伤害我妈妈
He didn't hurt my mom.
是闪电中的那个男人
It was the man in the lightning.
闪电人杀了我妈妈
The lightning man killed my mom.
-巴里 看着我 -不是我爸爸
- Barry, look at me. - Not my dad.
看着我
Look at me.
你帮不了我
You can't help me.
好吗 现在乔负责照顾你
Okay? Now Joe's gonna look after you
直到我离开这
until I can get out of here.
你要做个好孩子 我和你妈妈知道你是
You just be the good boy that your mom and I know you are.
爸爸
Dad?
警长 那个持枪歹徒被逮捕了吗
Detective, was the gunman apprehended?
那个持枪歹徒现在行踪不明
The shooter's whereabouts are unknown at this time.
英雄警察拯救斯塔格总裁
我们认为他有武装并且极其危险
We consider him armed and extremely dangerous.
谢谢 不再多回答问题了
Thank you. No more questions.
干得好 埃迪
Nice work, Eddie.
呐 不过是天时地利而已
Nah. Right place, right time.
不 你今天是个英雄
No, you were a hero today.
中城警局还有一个杀人凶手在逃
CCPD still has a killer on the loose.
我得回管辖区了
I should get back to the precinct.
好的
Okay.
那么你是过来喝咖啡的呢
So did you come here for caffeine,
还是你终于要告诉我你发生什么事了
or are you finally gonna tell me what's going on with you?
斯塔格先生 我希望你能
Mr. Stagg, I wish you would
重新考虑一下我们提供的保护性拘留
reconsider our offer for protective custody.
丹顿 布莱克已经证明他要动手杀人了
Danton Black has proven he is willing to kill,
并且他也有了 呃 伙伴们
and he's got uh... Friends.
相信我 他们都很危险
And trust me, they're all dangerous.
我已经加强了我的安保 警长
I've increased my security, Detective.
我倒是希望布莱克能来找麻烦
I hope black comes looking for trouble.
因为他能找到很多麻烦
'Cause he'll find plenty.
说得像个真正的慈善家一样
Spoken like a true philanthropist.
或者是人道主义者 嗯
Or is it humanitarian? Ah.
抱歉 我总是记不得
I'm sorry. I can never remember
哪一个才是你的伪装 西蒙
which one you're pretending to be, Simon.
哈里森
Harrison...
不用起来送了
Don't get up.
呵呵
Ha-ha!
你的另一位粉丝吗 博士
Another fan of yours, Doctor?
我们能谈谈吗 警长
Can we talk, Detective?
你是对的
So you were right.
巴里不是唯一的超自然人
Barry's not the only one who's special.
今天这个试图谋杀西蒙 斯塔格的人 他能
This guy that tried to kill Simon Stagg today, he could--
自发地自我复制
Replicate spontaneously.
是 我们知道了
Yeah, we know.
你一开始就知道巴里会这样吗
Did you know about Barry?
当他刚开始陷入昏迷的时候
When he was first in his coma
你来到了医院 你问我
you came to the hospital, and you asked me
你能否带他去科技之星实验室
if you could take him to S.T.A.R. Labs.
你那时就知道了他的能力吗
Did you know what he could do?
我有怀疑他
I had my suspicions that he was...
被影响了
affected.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
嘿 乔
Hey, Joe...
我从来没有想过要成为
I was never looking to become the senior member
打击秘密犯罪的组织的组建人员
of a secret crime fighting unit.
你和我都知道
You and I both know
我们是唯一有能力保护中城的一群人
we are the only ones equipped to protect Central City.
也许我对保护巴里更感兴趣
Maybe I'm more interested in protecting Barry.
但是显而易见的 他却要全副武装起来
But of course he's all set to fly
和你一起奔赴火场
into the fire right along with you.
不 他不会
No, he's not.
以后不会了 他退出了
Not anymore. He quit.
他没告诉你吗
He didn't tell you?
我还没见过他
I haven't seen him.
我相信这只是暂时的
Well I'm sure it's only temporary.
从我对巴里的了解来看
From what I know of Barry,
当他决心要做一件事的时候
when he sets his mind to something...
没有人能够说服他放弃
No one's gonna talk him out of it.
但是下次当他穿好装备
But the next time he suits up...
咻
Fshh!
莽撞地冲向危险
Runs headlong into danger...
他将会失败
He will fail.
为什么
Why?
他觉得他做不到
He doesn't think he's capable.
怀疑
Doubt...
是他真正的敌人
Is his real enemy.
乔 不是外面的什么潜藏的敌人
Joe, not whatever's lurking out there.
而是只要你继续怀疑他
And as long as you continue to doubt him,
他就会一直怀疑他自己
he'll keep doubting himself.
还有我郑重声明
And for the record...
我也关心他
I care about him, too.
我猜你饿坏了
Guess you were hungry.
- 压力性进食 -啊
- Stress eating. - Ah.
我是来道歉的
I came to say I'm sorry.
你是对的 是我冷漠了
And you're right. I have been distant.
- 对的 - 一个混球
- Correct. - Kind of a jerk.
你应该更经常地道歉
You should apologize more often.
你真的挺擅长道歉的
You are really sensational at it.
嗯
Hmm.
嗯 所以
Hmm. So...
那天的事你有什么要告诉我的吗
What were you going to tell me the other day?
我想我有些事要做
I thought I had to do something.
我认为非常重要的事
Something I thought was important,
但结果是我并不是很擅长
but it turns out that I'm not very good at it.
但我擅长的是做你的朋友
But what I am good at is being your friend.
所以如果你需要我帮你
So if you need help coming up with
的文章想一个新的主题 -- 我找到了一个
a new topic for your article-- I found one.
实际让我感兴趣的
Something that actually interests me.
我知道这听起来很疯狂
I know this is gonna sound crazy...
它已经在本周遍及互联网了
It's been all over the Internet this week.
在大楼火灾中
At a building fire...
在银行劫案中
At a bank heist...
甚至在那天晚上那些劫匪
Even the other night when those robbers
向警卫开枪的时候
shot at the security guard,
他说他被飞快移动到外面
he said he was whooshed outside.
有什么人在那里救人
Something out there is saving people.
我认为你从事新闻工作
I thought you were taking journalism.
而不是写科幻小说
Not science fiction writing.
从我认识你开始
Ever since I have known you
你就一直相信那些不可思议之事
you have believed in the impossible.
如果你是对的呢
What if you were right?
如果关于那天晚上你妈妈的死你是对的呢
What if you were right about the night that your mom died?
科技之星实验室
听着 我告诉过你们我不干了
Look, I told you I'm through.
我知道 但你需要到科技之星实验室
I know, but you need to get to S.T.A.R. Labs
立刻
right now.
- 巴里 没事的 - 这怎么是没事
- Barry, it's okay. - It is not okay.
布莱克在这里 他就 站在这里
Black is here, and he's just...standing there.
这不是他 是吧
That's not him, is it?
这是他的一个复制品
It's one of his replicates.
从哪来的
How did you get it?
我造出来的
I grew him.
我从你的套装上提取了布莱特的一个血液样本
I isolated a sample of Black's blood from you suit
看看我能不能触发它体外培养
to see if I could trigger the in vitro cultivation process
好研究一下布莱克是如何复制的
and learn how Black multiplies.
所以我把目标细胞系涂布在蛋白凝胶上
So I exposed the target cells to a protein gel,
它们就开始复制了
and they began replicating...
变成这样
Into that.
为什么他
Why isn't he...
它什么都不能做
It doing anything?
我们做了脑部扫描
We did a brain scan.
无意识运动的功能区是活跃的 其他几乎什么都没有
Involuntary motor functions are active, little else.
我们认为它像是一个接受器
We think it's acting as a receiver.
没有布莱克这个复制就品是一个空壳
The clones are an empty shell without Black.
搞定真正的布莱克
Shut down the real Black,
可能就能把他们全部搞定
and you might shut them all down.
但是我们怎么知道哪个才是真正的丹东 布莱克
But how do we know which one's the real Danton Black?
是你的晕厥情况给了我启发
That occurred to me given your own passing out.
布莱克有极限的 就像你一样
Black has limits, just like you.
控制他所有的克隆体
Controlling all of those clones
必须要消耗大量的体力
must require a tremendous amount of physical strength.
因此 找出有虚弱和疲劳迹象的那一个
So, look for the one showing signs of weakness or fatigue.
他就是本体
He's the prime.
只是一个理论
Just a theory...
但是我觉得你可能愿意尝试一下的 艾伦先生
But one you might want to put to the test, Mr. Allen.
另外 我把这些高卡路里的蛋白质棒
Plus, I whipped up these high- calorie protein bars
给你维持你的新陈代谢
for you to keep your metabolism up.
嗯
Ah!
还有吗
Any more of them?
没了
Nope.
为什么它开始移动了
Why did it start moving?
主体
The prime.
我猜测 因为主体在移动
My guess is, the prime is on the move.
这一个听到了战斗的召唤
This one heard the summons to battle.
我知道他要被召唤去哪
And I know where he was summoned to.
斯塔特工业
Stagg Industries.
你应该报告给局里
You should call it in.
警察不能与这些抗衡
Police can't fight this.
布莱克现在的变化 像马顿兄弟那样
What Black's become, like Mardon...
已经不是我力所能及的
Beyond me.
可能也不是他们力所能及的
Maybe way beyond them, too.
唯一一个没有被超越的人
The only person it's not beyond
是你
is you.
你应该去做这件事 我理解
You gotta do this. I get it.
所有你有生以来就这么一次 照我说的去做
So for once in your life, do what I tell you to do.
去阻止他
Go stop him.
明早把那些数据给我 可以吗
Just get me those figures by morning, okay?
站住 不许动
Freeze. Don't move.
你好 丹顿
Hello, Danton.
再见 西蒙
Goodbye, Simon.
呆在这儿
Stay here.
我知道斯塔特窃取了你的研究成果
I know Stagg stole your research,
但这并没有赋予你权利去谋杀他
but that doesn't give you the right to murder.
你以为这是因为我的工作
You think this is about my job.
啊
Aah!
这是为了伊丽莎白
This is about Elizabeth.
她是我的妻子
She was my wife.
她得了一种退行性冠状动脉疾病。
She had a degenerative coronary disease.
她的名字已经在器官移植的列表上还几年了 但是
She'd been on the transplant list for years, but...
快没有时间了
Time was running out.
如果我再不能帮她弄一个新的心脏
So if I couldn't get her a new heart...
那你就要为她培植一个是吗
You were gonna grow her one.
我就快要成功了
I was so close.
直到斯塔特窃取了我的研究
Until Stagg stole my research.
这样他就可以获得荣誉
So he could reap the glory.
而我只能亲手葬送我最好的朋友
And I got to bury my best friend.
现在
Now...
我孑然一身了
I'm alone.
记住 巴里 要找到本体
Remember, Barry. Find the prime.
这里有太多的复制品了
There's too many of them to fight.
巴里 你得隔离主体
Barry, you need to isolate the prime.
我做不到 这不可能
I can't. It's impossible.
一切皆有可能 巴里 这是你教我的
Nothing's impossible, Barry. You taught me that.
你能够做到的
You can do this.
巴里
Barry.
巴里 你还好吗
Barry, are you all right?
我没事
I'm fine.
搞定了
It's done.
坚持住
Hang on!
不
No!
别
Don't.
市中心警察官员们现在确认
Central City police officials are now confirming
前雇员丹顿 布莱克-- 试图去救他
former employee Danton Black-- tried to save him.
但他不想被救
Doesn't sound like he wanted to be saved.
有些人 一旦他们受伤了
Some people, when they break...
就再也无法复原
They can't be put together again.
但有些人复原之后却能变得更加强大
Some people heal even stronger.
希望如此
I hope so.
至少 分身人不会
Well, at least multiplex
再伤害到任何人
won't be able to hurt anyone else.
告诉你我会想到了一个很酷的名字
Told you I'd come up with a cool name.
好吧 我可能是那个穿着制服奔跑的人
Yeah, I may be the one in the suit doing all the running...
但是当我在外面帮助别人 改变世界的时候
But when I'm out there helping people, making a difference...
你们都和我并肩作战
You're all out there with me.
最终我意识到了一些事
Finally realized something,
我们都被那道闪电击中了
we were all struck by that lightning.
饿么
Hungry?
意大利辣肠味 橄榄味
Pepperoni, olives...
和墨西哥辣椒味
And jalapeo.
你会喜欢的口味
Just like you like it.
谢谢
Thank you.
你错了
You were wrong.
这周我错了很多
I have been wrong a lot this week.
你最好再详细一点
You're gonna have to be more specific.
你说你不能帮助你爸爸的这件事
You said that one of things driving you
一直困扰着你
to run around out there was that you couldn't help your dad.
你可以帮他的
You can help him.
我们可以的
We can.
我们会找出那晚是
We're gonna figure out
谁或什么东西杀了你的妈妈
who or what killed your mother that night.
然后我们会把你爸爸从监狱里救出来
And then we're gonna get your father out of prison.
我们一起
Together.
乔 我说过你不是我的爸爸
Joe, what I said about you not being my father--
巴里 我知道
Barry, I know.
我知道我不是你的爸爸
I know I'm not your father.
你是对的 你不是
You're right. You're not.
你只是一个给我
You're just... The man who kept me fed
温饱的人
and in clothes...
那个晚上会因为我怕黑
Who sat beside my bed at night until I fell asleep
坐在我床边陪我直到我入睡的人
because I was afraid of the dark...
教我写作业的人
helped me with my homework...
你教我怎样开车 怎样刮胡子
You taught me how to drive and shave...
还送我上大学
And you dropped me off at college.
对我来说就像个父亲
Sounds a lot like a dad to me.
每个小孩都梦想成为超级英雄
Every kid dreams of being a superhero.
拥有力量 拯救人类
Having powers. Saving people.
但是没有孩子想过当他们成为英雄却无法拯救人类时
But no kid thinks about what it's like when you're a hero
会是什么样子
and you're not saving people.
事实是
Truth is...
其他的一切都没有什么变化
Not much else changes.
你依旧会受伤 你依然会爱
You still hurt. You still love.
你还是祈祷 希望和害怕事情
You still wish and hope and fear things.
你依旧需要有人来和你共度一切
And you still need people to help you with all of it.
就某些方面来说 那是最美之处
In some ways, that's the best part.
巴里 一辆装甲车刚刚在格里芬大道被劫持
Barry, an armored car was just hijacked on Griffin Avenue.
你立马过去那里
Get your ass over there.
收到 事实上
I got it. Actually...
最美的地方
The best part?
就是这个
It's this.
韦尔斯
Wells...
谁让你进来的
Who the hell let you in here?
外面在开派对吗
You been having a party out there?
我确定你在电视上看到了
I'm sure you saw on TV.
我的一个前雇员企图杀了我
A former employee of mine tried to kill me.
那个有分身能力的前雇员
Former employee with the ability to replicate...
与一个能超速移动的人对持
Faced off against a man who could move at super speed.
你也看见他了 对吧
You've seen him too, haven't you?
确实 我看见了
Indeed, I have.
超凡的力量
Extraordinary.
他所拥有的力量 就像
The power he possesses, it's like the--
就像古时候的神那样
it's like the Gods of old.
像墨丘利神降临地球
It's like Mercury on earth.
你能想象如果你能控制他的能力吗
Can you imagine if you could control his power?
如果你能 如果你能驾驭他
If you could--if you could harness it?
你能改变它对人类的意义
You could change what it means to be human.
戴着红色面具的人是关键
The man in a red mask is the key,
我要抓住他
and I'm gonna get him.
戴着红色面具的人
The man in the red mask.
他叫闪电侠
He's called the Flash.
至少
Or at least...
他总有一天会变成闪电侠
He will be one day.
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
原谅我 西蒙
Forgive me, Simon.
我担心你会觉得这是针对你个人的
I worry you think that you will think this is personal,
但这不是
and it's not.
这是为了那个戴着红色面具的人
It's just that the man in the red mask...
世上速度最快的人
The fastest man alive...
我必须保证
he must be kept...
他的安全
safe.